okay wait just let me get serious for a
minute hello today we're gonna talk
about Mary Dyer Mary Dyer and her
husband William moved to Massachusetts
from England and they were Quakers which
is more liberal Puritans so will.i.am a
merrier like this fun and great the
Puritans are the people that settled New
England in the 1600s Puritans
were like the Bible is the Word of God
like literally God dictated some notes
to his secretary Mary was just like I've
got a little bit of a different take on
it hey you know this thing the Holy
Spirit we keep hearing about that's
within you oh my god the Holy Spirit's
reign here yeah you can just talk to it
oh my god hey Holy Spirit the thing is
what she's doing is illegal there is no
separation of church and state so the
guys that ran New England were like no
no no no don't go just saying oh here's
my interpretation of it and have women
over 40 no you're you're undermining the
whole thing okay so Mary was banished
she's like fine no big don't banish me
I'm gonna Rhode Island what I want is
everyone to understand is what Mary did
to the Puritan dudes she freaked their
dicks off okay because you don't
understand its are like um didn't we
tell you leave she's like yeah
but I'm not trying mean dick but I'm
coming back to ask you can you please
just have you don't have to like be into
it but can you please have religious
tolerance and they're like no you know
they said we're gonna kill you we're
gonna strangle you noose you what do you
call it kill you kill yourself murder
you
gallows she's gonna get hung Mary was
getting it huh she's walking with the
guy to the gallows and they literally
the noose is around her neck and they're
like Mary if you promise to leave
Massachusetts Bay Colony and never come
back you can go
and she was like okay I know I alright
they take the rope off around her neck
and they let her go Mary did an amazing
thing oh do you think I should go to
Mary Dyer comes back to Massachusetts
and says I didn't deal with these laws
to their bloody face I'm gonna bloody
deal with these laws in the face in
other words I'm confronting the head
obviously laying on the floor like this
is one of the best times I've had in a
long time
so Mary she's visiting Quakers in prison
they were like thank you Mary for coming
cuz we get that you get what we're going
through which is like totally
so the Commonwealth of Massachusetts was
like stop visiting prisoners stopped
acting like it's okay we got it kill you
so he walked her to the gallows on
Boston Common in 1660
and they put the noose around your neck
so she had the rope around her neck like
about to die
she said no ear can hear no tongue can
taste no heart can understand then join
something like the joy but know the joy
and the treasures of the blessings and
the refreshments I don't care what that
is but the refreshments of God then I
have starting rape this
[Music]
and then they count on her everyone's
watching
oh my god we're on the Boston Common
we're watching someone die that's the
problem being a sec and then King
Charles was like excuse me what the
everyone doing over in Massachusetts I
didn't say this should get so crazy
don't kill people that makes you look
more like a if you didn't know by
the way dudes but she changed the world
but you'll never hear about it anywhere
but here
well she's gonna unmarked grave on the
Boston Common and you know whose grave
is marked Jim Morrison people live in
Europe
[Music]
you